<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: psychology | ForgeBrain]]></title>
  <link href="http://coolbrain.github.com/blog/categories/psychology/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://coolbrain.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-08-04T01:17:00+08:00</updated>
  <id>http://coolbrain.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[ForgeBrain]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movies]]></title>
    <link href="http://coolbrain.github.com/blog/2013/07/05/movies/"/>
    <updated>2013-07-05T09:51:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://coolbrain.github.com/blog/2013/07/05/movies</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote><p><p>大学看的电影比较多，不过能在脑海中留下印记的只有那些能够触动心灵的经典，所以对于其它一般的电影，又何必浪费时间去看？因为其一文不值、一无是处。</p>
<p>《毕业生》展示了一个大学生毕业后的迷惘，在受到性的诱惑下，居然和你一个有夫之妇搞上关系。而后来这个毕业生追求其女儿，但东窗事发，此家庭坚决拒绝他。但他坚定不移，最终有情人终成眷属。背景音乐是《斯卡布罗集市》，he once was a true love of mine.</p>
<!-- more -->
<p>《教父I、II、II》说的是意大利黑帮的崛起，为了保护家族的利益，不仅要有一个运筹帷幄、忍辱负重的领导，而且整个家族要众志成城,才不至于淹没在弱肉强食的社会。</p>
<p>《美国往事》这与美国梦扯上点关系。几个在纽约街头的小混混，以noodle为头，结识了一个非常厉害的小混混，他带大家挣大钱。可惜，最后大家都被他玩弄于股掌之间，其之后金盘洗手，进入美国政界，成为美国商务部长。曾经打家劫舍，奸淫掳掠的小混混，脱身一变成为一个“字字珠玑”、彬彬有礼的政界大腕。而noodle则是潜逃了二十年，才知道事实的真相，曾经noodle靠暴力才得到其女朋友的肉体，而之后，二十年，其女朋友甘心做欺骗其二十年的商务部长的情妇。这个厉害的小混混，通过自己的方法、努力，不但得到金钱、地位、还轻易得到别人女友的心，这就是导演所展示的美国梦。</p>
<p>《辛德勒的名单》说的是一个工厂老板为了救更多的犹太人，不惜与法西斯竭力周旋，展开斗智斗勇的历程。</p>
<p>《乱世佳人》其实自己一直追求的人不是自己所要的，反而他人追求自己，此人需要慎重考虑，不要总是拒之千里之外，他会静悄悄，毫不留情地走掉。</p>
<p>《肖申克的救赎》主人公被冤枉，且在监狱受尽折磨，但却心存希望，自己有逃出去的一日。果然老天不负有心人，其成功逃出魔鬼的掌心。</p>
<p>《洛奇》主人公告诉我们心里还有些东西还没有释放出来，要将其释放，心灵才会觉得舒服。生活并不只是有快乐，而且有接踵而来的痛苦，在痛苦的时候，不要抱怨现实、他人，而是继续前行。</p>
<p>《美丽心灵》他是聪明绝顶的人，但他也逃脱不了所谓的压力，他拥有美好的爱情，他有自己的学术地位，但他却有了幻想症，在妻子的不离不弃的帮助下，其终于站起来。</p>
<p>《百万宝贝》主人公冒着生命危险去改变自己的命运，同时也改善了家庭的条件，可惜当出现挫折时，家人不理解、抛弃她，她只有在医院绝望地结束自己。</p>
<p>《当幸福来敲门》主人公是一个坚持自己信念，穷且益坚的人，其最终实现了自己的理想。当别人说你不可以的时候，记得去保护自己的梦想和去实现它。</p>
<p>《心灵捕手》通过解读自己心灵，坦诚地说出来，来做出正确的抉择。</p>
<p>《风雨哈佛路》女主人公生于不幸的家庭，妈妈戒不掉毒瘾，最终一命呜呼。但她却是生于淤泥而不染，继续自己的风雨路。</p>
<p>《国王的演讲》一个口吃的国王，在二战英国受难时，挺身而出，最终成为一个吐字清晰的国王。</p>
<p>《霸王别姬》人如戏，戏如生。</p>
<p>...这么多的电影，就总结了这么多，实在太小太小，太不可思议。真是光阴似箭，岁月如梭！</p></p></blockquote>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Procrastination]]></title>
    <link href="http://coolbrain.github.com/blog/2013/06/09/procrastination/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-09T20:36:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://coolbrain.github.com/blog/2013/06/09/procrastination</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote><p><p>按照百度百科的解释，单纯地做事拖拉或是懒得去做，只能定义为“拖延”，也仅是一种坏习惯，改正它并不难。<strong>当“拖延”已经影响到情绪，如出现强烈自责情绪，强烈负罪感，不断的自我否定、自我贬低，伴生出焦虑症、抑郁症等心理疾病时，才能称之为“拖延症”</strong>。</p>
<!-- more -->
<p>拖延的基础，实际上是对自身很高甚至不切实际的期望，如果说完成任务是走过一块一人宽、十米长的厚木板，那么当它放在地面上时，几乎人人都可以轻松地走过，但对结果的高期望则像是将这块木板架到了两座高楼间十层楼高的地方，于是我们会害怕掉下来，即害怕失败或害怕成功，甚至不敢向前迈上一步，而deadline则是身后的一团火，当它离我们足够近时，害怕被烧着的恐惧感战胜了对掉下去的恐惧感，于是我们一下子冲了过去，在deadline前赶完了任务，尽管质量难说。 </p>
<p>更可怕的是，很多拖延的人甚至很享受那种deadline过后突然一下放松的感觉，而且拖延的结果有时反而挺好。这种时候，会在心里表扬自己很有“效率”。同时，长期这样下去，尽管不愿承认，但潜意识里确实觉得自己如果花了很多时间成绩却平平，会是一件非常丢脸的事情。于是这一切的一切，都再次强化的拖延。</p>
<p>拖延症之歌</p>
<p>See I have to write this essay </p>
<p>that the teacher gave last week </p>
<p>and it's due tomorrow morning </p>
<p>twenty pages all in Greek </p>
<p>Nah but first I check my Tumblur</p>
<p>Facebook,Twitter, call my Mom </p>
<p>Then just one more, one more page</p>
<p>oh I waste so much time dot com </p>
<p>I'm procrastinating</p>
<p>All day I sit here waiting</p>
<p>for just the perfect moment to begin</p>
<p>we're procrastinating</p>
<p>Why work, we could be gaming</p>
<p>Agreed! Procrastinating FTM!</p>
<p>I have to start this diet</p>
<p>cause my prom's a week away</p>
<p>So I'm only eating veggies</p>
<p>and I'm starting that today</p>
<p>But I'm getting really hungry</p>
<p>and those cookies look sublime</p>
<p>Fine,I'll have just one, or two, or ten</p>
<p>Why not?It's not crime!<p>
<p>We're procrasinating</p>
<p>No better way than eating</p>
<p>cause nothing else could possibly compare</p>
<p>I'm procrastinating</p>
<p>It's really fascinating</p>
<p>I know there's work to do but I don't care</p>
<p>I should probably do my laundry</p>
<p>I should probably feed my cat</p>
<p>But right now we're playing Halo</p>
<p>YOLO! Headshot! Take that!</p>
<p>You should probably call the doctor</p>
<p>Never mind it's just a scratch</p>
<p>But your arm's gone</p>
<p>It's a flesh wound</p>
<p>Now come on let's play some catch!</p>
<p>I have organized my desktop</p>
<p>Now I'm all set up to work</p>
<p>Wait that picture's kinda crooked</p>
<p>and it's driving me berserk</p>
<p>Now I might as well just color code</p>
<p>my pencils one by one</p>
<p>and my papers and my files</p>
<p>I can't work until it's done!</p>
<p>We're procrastinating</p>
<p>All day I sit here waiting</p>
<p>for just the perfect moment to begin</p>
<p>We're procrastinating</p>
<p>Wait!</p>
<p>You're procratinating right now</p>
<p>You're procratinating</p>
<p>Why are you still here watching?</p>
<p>I'm sure that you've got things due long ago</p>
<p>You're procratinating</p>
<p>Please leave a thumbs up rating</p>
<p>Go do your work</p>
<p>Tomorrow!</p>
<p>大学最后论文阶段，我患上了严重的拖延症，导致焦虑，自我否定，最终论文质量大打折扣。因为心情不好，遇到挫折后，就不断拖延，直至弄出个大头佛。大学不但失败，而且被别人冷朝热讽，人啊，要有所兼顾，但要做最重要的事情，不要本末倒置，不然适得其反；戒骄戒躁，坚持前行;不要轻信人言，要懂得分析；不要感情用事，用行动改变现状！</p>
<p><strong>与其沉沉闷闷地抱怨人生,不如轰轰烈烈地扭转乾坤</strong></p></p></blockquote>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Goal-Setting Process]]></title>
    <link href="http://coolbrain.github.com/blog/2013/05/23/goal-setting-process/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-23T22:58:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://coolbrain.github.com/blog/2013/05/23/goal-setting-process</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote><p><p>This passage is talking about Goal-Setting Process.(字字珠玑）</p>
<p>1.<strong>Decide exactly what you want in every key area of your life.</strong>(心之所向） Start off by idealing.</p>
<p>2.<strong>write it down.</strong>(好记性不如烂笔头） They must be clear, specific, detailed and measurable.</p>
<!-- more -->
<p>3.<strong>set a deadline.</strong>(末日将至) Your subsconscious mind uses deadlines as "forcing systems " to drive you, consciously and unconsciously toward achieving your goal on scheduler.</p>
<p>4.<strong>Identity the obstacles that you will have to overcome to achieve your goal.</strong>(知己知彼、百战不殆） Only 20% of the reasons you are not achieving your goal are on the outside. Always start with yourself.The 80/20 Rule applied to constraints.</p>
<p>5.<strong>Identity the knowledge, information and skills you will need to achieve your goal.</strong>（未雨绸缪) Especially, identify the skills that you will have to develop to be in the top 10% of your field. </p>
<p>6.<strong>Identity the people whose help and cooperation you will acquire to achieve your goal.</strong>(三顾茅庐、合作无间） One key person at a certain time and place in your life will make all the difference. </p>
<p>7.<strong>Make a list of everything you will have to do to achieve your goal.</strong> "(步步为营） A journey of  a thousand miles begin with a single step". You can build the biggest wall in the world one brick at a time. </p>
<p>8.<strong>Organize your list into a plan.</strong>（举足轻重） You organize this list by arranging the steps that you have identified by sequence and priority. The 80/20 Rule says that 80% of your result will come from 20% of your activities.</p>
<p>9.<strong>Make a plan.</strong> （一气呵成）Organize your list into a series of steps from the beginning all the way through to the completion of your goal. </p>
<p>10.<strong>Select your number one, most important task for each day.</strong>（明察秋毫、井然有条、重点优先）Set priorities on your list using the 80/20 rule.</p>
<p>11.<strong>Develop the habit of self-discipline.</strong>（三思而后行，吾日三省吾身） Once you have decide on your most important task. Resolve to concentrate singled-mindedly on that one task until it is 100% completed.</p>
<p>12.<strong>Practise visualization on your goals.</strong>（望梅止渴） Create clear, vivid, exciting, emotional picture of your goals as if they were already a reality.<p>
<p>根据自己的兴趣爱好，定好计划，排号优先级，实现自己的目标。且不断改善自身，自律，约束自己的行为举止，同时也要懂得和别人相处和交流。有时候，要想自己实现目标的快乐，这样才能使自己更加有动力，对未来更加之憧憬，对现在更加是珍惜。</p>
<p><strong>Motto: No man's education is ever finished. A man's reading program should be as carefully planned as his daily diet, for that too is food, without which he cannot mentally develop.</strong> </p></p></blockquote>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Places of Historical Interest]]></title>
    <link href="http://coolbrain.github.com/blog/2013/05/06/places-of-historical-interest/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-06T20:14:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://coolbrain.github.com/blog/2013/05/06/places-of-historical-interest</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote><p><p>If I have a dream, I should keep and protect it. Don't let myself down. The outside world is beatiful, wonderful and unbelievable. Could I always keep hope in my heart? It's easy to give up, to walk away; but it's hard to stay, live and make things better. Don't think about myself. Think about my parents, the people around me. Am I worthy? </p>
<!-- more -->
<p>2013.6月我去深圳的世界之窗，发现原来里面全是世界名胜古迹的赝品，在这里已经流连忘返、乐在其中，更何况是真正的名胜古迹。要知道自己的世界是由自己决定，是否成为井底之蛙，或者"会当凌绝顶，一览众山小",就看自己的选择。只是仰慕、瞻仰是不够的，要有切实的行动。不单单是这样的事情，更多的事情也有现在的状态去决定。</p>
<p>I want to show some photos to inspire myself. Many great places are waiting me to see.</p>
U.S Congress, the symbol of American democracy
<img src="http://coolbrain.github.com/assets/images/place/U.S_Congress.jpg"  alt="U.S_Congress"/>
Washington Monument
<img src="http://coolbrain.github.com/assets/images/place/Washington_Monument.jpg"  alt="Washington_Monument"/>
Lincoln Memorial. Lincoln is the most respectable president in America. History witnesses this great man. One hundred year later, Martin Luther King gave a great speech 《 I have a dream 》 at this place, 28 August 1963.
<img src="http://coolbrain.github.com/assets/images/place/Lincoln_Memorial.jpg"  alt="Lincoln_Memorial"/>
Golden Gate Brige
<img src="http://coolbrain.github.com/assets/images/place/Golden_Gate_Bridge.jpg"  alt="Golden_Gate_Bridge"/>
Canyonlands Utah. Natural scenary
<img src="http://coolbrain.github.com/assets/images/place/Canyonlands.jpg"  alt="Canyonlands"/>
Maine Coast
<img src="http://coolbrain.github.com/assets/images/place/Maine_coast.jpg"  alt="Maine_coast"/>
River Thames, London
<img src="http://coolbrain.github.com/assets/images/place/River_Thames.jpg"  alt="River_Thames"/>
Millennium Bridge
<img src="http://coolbrain.github.com/assets/images/place/Millennium_Bridge.jpg"  alt="Millennium_Bridge"/>
Buckingham Palace
<img src="http://coolbrain.github.com/assets/images/place/Buckingham_Palace.jpg"  alt="Buckingham_Palace"/>
Standing gaurd, Ancient Egypt
<img src="http://coolbrain.github.com/assets/images/place/Standing_gaurd.jpg"  alt="Standing_gaurd"/>
Temple of Horus
<img src="http://coolbrain.github.com/assets/images/place/Temple_of_Horus.jpg"  alt="Temple_of_Horus"/>
Architectural marvel
<img src="http://coolbrain.github.com/assets/images/place/Architectural_marvel.jpg"  alt="Architectural_marvel"/>
Christ the Redeemer, Brazil
<img src="http://coolbrain.github.com/assets/images/place/Christ_the_Redeemer.jpg"  alt="Christ_the_Redeemer"/>
<p>人生有几多个十年？最紧要要过得痛快。其实很多的话都是meaningless，不会produce any effect，但好像我这样的人，就当作宝了。一个人不meditate，reflect，其实就不算人了，与动物无异。在历史面前，谦卑，景仰和沉思。</p>
<p>希望听起这首背景曲调时，会想起某些事，某些人，谁有能理解谁呢？时代已变，以前想都不敢想的观念，现在已经深入人心，但这个时代也有这时代的局限，让人觉得透不过起来，是啊，假如人不能适应现时代，那就--闷闷不乐，郁郁寡欢。<a href="http://dabaoku.com/dabaoku/uploads/soft/yinxiao/beijing/166.mp3">金枝欲攀叹调.</a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.nbcnews.com/id/6981409/ns/travel-travel_photos/">Reference Source:traval_photos</a></p></p></blockquote>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Depression]]></title>
    <link href="http://coolbrain.github.com/blog/2013/04/26/depression/"/>
    <updated>2013-04-26T17:59:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://coolbrain.github.com/blog/2013/04/26/depression</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote><p><p>The famous song BOAST of Eason origin from Depression which was written the night of April 1st,2003 by C.Y.Kong who was one of best friends of Leslie committed suicide that day. C.Y.Kong could't understand leslie's decision and wrote a song with ghostly synth to ask him or in memory of him. Eason liked the key change and the style of the song. He wrote some words for the song and Wyman helped him finish off what he wrote.This is how BOAST produced.Please appreciate<a href="http://www.cykong.com/Projects/Audio/Depression(DemoMelody).mp3">The orginal demo</a>  C.Y.Kong's Note: To me, this demo will always be dedicated to leslie.</p>
<!-- more -->
<p>浮夸歌词，because I am addicted to this song and willing to translate to English.</p>
有人问我我就会讲 但是无人来
<p>if someone ask me, I will talk, but no one come</p>
我期待 到无奈 有话要讲 得不到装载
<p>I expect unitl feel helpless. even with words, no chance to express</p>
我的心情犹豫像樽盖 等被揭开
<p>the mood is like bottle to be opened</p>
咀巴却在养青苔
<p>but the mouth is growing moss and mushroom</p>
人潮内愈文静 愈变得不受理睬
<p>the more silent in crowd, the fewer people care of you</p>
自己要搞出意外
<p>make accidents by myself</p>
像突然 地高歌
<p>like singing loudly and suddenly</p>
任何地方也像开四面台
<p>anywhere is like having performace in all directions</p>
着最闪的衫 扮十分感慨
<p>wear colorful clothes, diguise as being filled with one thousand regrets</p>
有人来拍照要记住插袋
<p>put hands into pockets when someone is coming to take photos</p>
你当我是浮夸吧 夸张只因我很怕
<p>you treat me as boast, boast as I am deadly fear</p>
似木头 似石头的话 得到注意吗
<p>if like wood or stone, am I get caution </p>
其实怕被忘记 至放大来演吧
<p>actually I perform exaggerately as afraid to be forgotten</p>
很不安 怎去优雅
<p>deadly upset, how can I be elegant</p>
世上还赞颂沉默吗
<p>does the world still praise silence</p>
不够爆炸 怎麽有话题
<p>not explosive enough, are there any topic</p>
让我夸做大娱乐家
<p>let me boast to be big entertainer</p>
那年十八 母校舞会 站着如喽罗
<p>stand as monkey when eighteen in old school's ball</p>
那时候 我含泪发誓各位 必须看到我
<p>in that time, refrain from tears and swear everyone must see me in the future </p>
在世间 平凡又普通的路太多
<p>there are too many plain and ordinary roads in this world</p>
屋村你住哪一座
<p>which road do you live in </p>
情爱中 工作中 受过的忽视太多
<p>suffer too much ignorance in love and work</p>
自尊已饱经跌堕 重视能治肚饿
<p>there is almost no respect in heart, paying much attention can cure hunger of stomach</p>
末曾获得过便知我为何 大动作很多
<p>not ever been gotten, you know me why I have so many big movements</p>
犯下这些错 搏人们看看我 算病态麽
<p>make these mistakes, let people judge me whether ill</p>
幸运儿并不多 若然未当过就知我为何
<p>there is not many lucky dog, if have not ever been, you know me why</p>
用十倍苦心 做突出一个
<p>to be prominent by ten times pains</p>
正常人够我富议论性么
<p>normal people is more controversive than me</p>
你叫我做浮夸吧 加几声嘘声也不怕
<p>you call me BOAST, don't be afraid to add some shushing </p>
我在场 有闷场的话
<p>if I am present and you feel bored</p>
表演你看吗 够歇斯底里 吗
<p>can I perform for you, and am I hysterical enough </p>
以眼泪淋花吧 一心只想你惊讶
<p>water flower with tears, wholeheartly just want you be suprised</p>
我旧时似未存在吗
<p>was I  existing as air in old times</p>
加重注码 青筋 也现形
<p>add note yards, blue veins also appear</p>
话我知 现在存在吗
<p>please tell me whether I am existing now</p>
凝视我 别再只看天花
<p>don't just only see smallpox when glazing at me</p>
我非你杯茶 也可尽情地喝吧
<p>I am not a cup of tea of yours, but you can drink it with abandon</p>
别遗忘有人在 为你 声沙
<p>don't forget someone hoarse for you</p>
<p>只因为听了《浮夸》,full of curiosity,search on the internet and know the detail of the song. 张国荣被港人尊称为“哥哥”。我觉得哥哥唱《the moon represent my heart》时，富含感情。哥哥拍的电影《霸王别姬》，简直就是曲高和众。不知道里面的虞姬是否是哥哥现实中的写照呢？哥哥从一而终，对京剧国粹的痴迷，执着，在清朝末代，北洋时期，国民党统治时期，抗日战争，内战，新中国，文革时期，依然没有糟蹋戏。假霸王，真虞姬。</p>
<p>电影中经典的台词：
<p>1.人得自个儿成全自个儿 </p>
<p>2.要想人前现贵，必先人后受罪 </p>
<p>3.我是假霸王，你是真虞姬 </p>
<p>4.不疯魔不成活 </p>
<p>5.自古人生在世，需有一技之能；我辈既务斯业，便当专心用功；以后名扬四海，根据即在年轻。</p>
<p>6.从一而终</p>
<p>哥哥在电影中扮演的虞姬，此一回眸...</p>
<img src="/assets/images/lesie.gif" alt="&quot;brother&quot;" /></p>

<p><p>PS：The Moon Represent my Heart歌词：</p>
你问我爱你有多深
<p>how deep I loved you </p>
我爱你有几分
<p>how strong emotion within myself</p>
<p>you are wondering </p>
我的情不移
<p>my feeling is true</p>
我的爱不变
<p>my love is never new</p>
月亮代表我的心
<p>the moon represents my heart</p>
你问我爱你有多深
<p>how deep I loved you</p>
我爱你有几分
<p>how strong emotion within myself</p>
<p>you want to know</p>
我的情不移
<p>my passion for you is real</p>
我的爱不变
<p>my devotion to you is a belief</p>
月亮代表我的心
<p>the moon represent my heart</p>
轻轻的一个吻
<p>a tender kiss</p>
已经打动我的心
<p>moved me to the heaven</p>
深深的一段情
<p>a loved story between you</p>
叫我思念到如今
<p>it's alive until today</p>
would you think so
<p>would you trust me</p></p></blockquote>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
