<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Psychology | ForgeBrain]]></title>
  <link href="http://coolbrain.github.com/blog/categories/psychology/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://coolbrain.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-02-23T16:06:04+08:00</updated>
  <id>http://coolbrain.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[ForgeBrain]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[拖延症前因后果]]></title>
    <link href="http://coolbrain.github.com/blog/2013/06/09/procrastination/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-09T20:36:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://coolbrain.github.com/blog/2013/06/09/procrastination</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote><p><p>按照百度百科的解释，单纯地做事拖拉或是懒得去做，只能定义为“拖延”，也仅是一种坏习惯，改正它并不难。<strong>当“拖延”已经影响到情绪，如出现强烈自责情绪，强烈负罪感，不断的自我否定、自我贬低，伴生出焦虑症、抑郁症等心理疾病时，才能称之为“拖延症”</strong>。</p>
<!-- more -->
<p>拖延的基础，实际上是对自身很高甚至不切实际的期望，如果说完成任务是走过一块一人宽、十米长的厚木板，那么当它放在地面上时，几乎人人都可以轻松地走过，但对结果的高期望则像是将这块木板架到了两座高楼间十层楼高的地方，于是我们会害怕掉下来，即害怕失败或害怕成功，甚至不敢向前迈上一步，而deadline则是身后的一团火，当它离我们足够近时，害怕被烧着的恐惧感战胜了对掉下去的恐惧感，于是我们一下子冲了过去，在deadline前赶完了任务，尽管质量难说。 </p>
<p>更可怕的是，很多拖延的人甚至很享受那种deadline过后突然一下放松的感觉，而且拖延的结果有时反而挺好。这种时候，会在心里表扬自己很有“效率”。同时，长期这样下去，尽管不愿承认，但潜意识里确实觉得自己如果花了很多时间成绩却平平，会是一件非常丢脸的事情。于是这一切的一切，都再次强化的拖延。</p>
<p>拖延症之歌</p>
<p>See I have to write this essay </p>
<p>that the teacher gave last week </p>
<p>and it's due tomorrow morning </p>
<p>twenty pages all in Greek </p>
<p>Nah but first I check my Tumblur</p>
<p>Facebook,Twitter, call my Mom </p>
<p>Then just one more, one more page</p>
<p>oh I waste so much time dot com </p>
<p>I'm procrastinating</p>
<p>All day I sit here waiting</p>
<p>for just the perfect moment to begin</p>
<p>we're procrastinating</p>
<p>Why work, we could be gaming</p>
<p>Agreed! Procrastinating FTM!</p>
<p>I have to start this diet</p>
<p>cause my prom's a week away</p>
<p>So I'm only eating veggies</p>
<p>and I'm starting that today</p>
<p>But I'm getting really hungry</p>
<p>and those cookies look sublime</p>
<p>Fine,I'll have just one, or two, or ten</p>
<p>Why not?It's not crime!<p>
<p>We're procrasinating</p>
<p>No better way than eating</p>
<p>cause nothing else could possibly compare</p>
<p>I'm procrastinating</p>
<p>It's really fascinating</p>
<p>I know there's work to do but I don't care</p>
<p>I should probably do my laundry</p>
<p>I should probably feed my cat</p>
<p>But right now we're playing Halo</p>
<p>YOLO! Headshot! Take that!</p>
<p>You should probably call the doctor</p>
<p>Never mind it's just a scratch</p>
<p>But your arm's gone</p>
<p>It's a flesh wound</p>
<p>Now come on let's play some catch!</p>
<p>I have organized my desktop</p>
<p>Now I'm all set up to work</p>
<p>Wait that picture's kinda crooked</p>
<p>and it's driving me berserk</p>
<p>Now I might as well just color code</p>
<p>my pencils one by one</p>
<p>and my papers and my files</p>
<p>I can't work until it's done!</p>
<p>We're procrastinating</p>
<p>All day I sit here waiting</p>
<p>for just the perfect moment to begin</p>
<p>We're procrastinating</p>
<p>Wait!</p>
<p>You're procratinating right now</p>
<p>You're procratinating</p>
<p>Why are you still here watching?</p>
<p>I'm sure that you've got things due long ago</p>
<p>You're procratinating</p>
<p>Please leave a thumbs up rating</p>
<p>Go do your work</p>
<p>Tomorrow!</p>
<p>大学最后论文阶段，我患上了严重的拖延症，导致焦虑，自我否定，最终论文质量大打折扣。因为心情不好，遇到挫折后，就不断拖延，直至弄出个大头佛。大学不但失败，而且被别人冷朝热讽，人啊，要有所兼顾，但要做最重要的事情，不要本末倒置，不然适得其反；戒骄戒躁，坚持前行;不要轻信人言，要懂得分析；不要感情用事，用行动改变现状！</p>
<p><strong>与其沉沉闷闷地抱怨人生,不如轰轰烈烈地扭转乾坤</strong></p></p></blockquote>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[设立目标的步骤]]></title>
    <link href="http://coolbrain.github.com/blog/2013/05/23/goal-setting-process/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-23T22:58:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://coolbrain.github.com/blog/2013/05/23/goal-setting-process</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote><p><p>This passage is talking about Goal-Setting Process.(字字珠玑）</p>
<p>1.<strong>Decide exactly what you want in every key area of your life.</strong>(心之所向） Start off by idealing.</p>
<p>2.<strong>write it down.</strong>(好记性不如烂笔头） They must be clear, specific, detailed and measurable.</p>
<!-- more -->
<p>3.<strong>set a deadline.</strong>(末日将至) Your subsconscious mind uses deadlines as "forcing systems " to drive you, consciously and unconsciously toward achieving your goal on scheduler.</p>
<p>4.<strong>Identity the obstacles that you will have to overcome to achieve your goal.</strong>(知己知彼、百战不殆） Only 20% of the reasons you are not achieving your goal are on the outside. Always start with yourself.The 80/20 Rule applied to constraints.</p>
<p>5.<strong>Identity the knowledge, information and skills you will need to achieve your goal.</strong>（未雨绸缪) Especially, identify the skills that you will have to develop to be in the top 10% of your field. </p>
<p>6.<strong>Identity the people whose help and cooperation you will acquire to achieve your goal.</strong>(三顾茅庐、合作无间） One key person at a certain time and place in your life will make all the difference. </p>
<p>7.<strong>Make a list of everything you will have to do to achieve your goal.</strong> "(步步为营） A journey of  a thousand miles begin with a single step". You can build the biggest wall in the world one brick at a time. </p>
<p>8.<strong>Organize your list into a plan.</strong>（举足轻重） You organize this list by arranging the steps that you have identified by sequence and priority. The 80/20 Rule says that 80% of your result will come from 20% of your activities.</p>
<p>9.<strong>Make a plan.</strong> （一气呵成）Organize your list into a series of steps from the beginning all the way through to the completion of your goal. </p>
<p>10.<strong>Select your number one, most important task for each day.</strong>（明察秋毫、井然有条、重点优先）Set priorities on your list using the 80/20 rule.</p>
<p>11.<strong>Develop the habit of self-discipline.</strong>（三思而后行，吾日三省吾身） Once you have decide on your most important task. Resolve to concentrate singled-mindedly on that one task until it is 100% completed.</p>
<p>12.<strong>Practise visualization on your goals.</strong>（望梅止渴） Create clear, vivid, exciting, emotional picture of your goals as if they were already a reality.<p>
<p>根据自己的兴趣爱好，定好计划，排号优先级，实现自己的目标。且不断改善自身，自律，约束自己的行为举止，同时也要懂得和别人相处和交流。有时候，要想自己实现目标的快乐，这样才能使自己更加有动力，对未来更加之憧憬，对现在更加是珍惜。</p>
<p><strong>Motto: No man's education is ever finished. A man's reading program should be as carefully planned as his daily diet, for that too is food, without which he cannot mentally develop.</strong> </p></p></blockquote>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
