<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: English | ForgeBrain]]></title>
  <link href="http://coolbrain.github.com/blog/categories/english/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://coolbrain.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-02-23T00:18:52+08:00</updated>
  <id>http://coolbrain.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[ForgeBrain]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[鞭辟入里	明辨事理]]></title>
    <link href="http://coolbrain.github.com/blog/2013/10/10/fact-opinion/"/>
    <updated>2013-10-10T22:36:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://coolbrain.github.com/blog/2013/10/10/fact-opinion</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote><p><p>when I read the passage, I always can't consciously distinguish the fact and opinion. Sometimes I think the author's personal opinion as the fact.if having chance to talk with other's, I boast about their opionion though I don't know which is original, objective or personal view.The most fearest thing is that I put them into practice and consequently find that they are wrong and liable and I have already wasted a lot of time and done harm to myself.</p>
<!-- more -->
<p>For example,"no man ever look at the world with pristine eyes. He sees it edited by a definite set of customs and institutions and ways of thinking." It sounds reasonable, and may be objective.To persuade reader, the author consequently list fact and eminent man's word to support his opinion. Our teacher taught us in junior school.</p>
<p>"Boardly speaking, human being may be divided into three classes:those who are toiled to death, those who are worried to death, and those who are bored to death."The author acquires this opinion according to his observation and reflection. Whatever, he spares no effort to supporting and describing his opinion."The seeds must be carefully chosen; they must fall on good ground;they must be sedulouly tended, if the vivifying fruits are to be at hand when needed." he uses metaphor describing the process of cultivating hobbies to make reader be aware of the importance of it.</p>
<p>"The undulating waves of the open sea are generated by three natural causes:wind, earth movements or tremors, and the gravitational pull of the moon and the sun."This is fact based on the result of current research which may be overthrowed in the future.It's natural phenomenon. "Appreciaton of sculpture depends upon the ability to respond to form in three dimensions." It seems opinion but it's fact.</p>
<p>"This is a sceptical age, but although our faith in many of the things in which our forefathers fervently believed has weakened, our confidence in the curative properties of the bootle of medicine remains the same as theirs".Why does the author have this opinion? "This modern faith in medicines is proved by the fact that the annual drug bill of the Health Services is mounting to astronomical figures and shows no signs at present of ceasing to rise." he gets it based on data which we can check on the internet. If the author want to cheat, he may forge some data or fact to support his opinion. Maybe we carelessly trust and suffer a lot.</p></p></blockquote>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
